Skyler Schuck

skyler.schuck@colostate.edu | skylerschuck.github.io | linkedin.com/in/skyler-schuck/

About Me

Experience in applied economic analysis & forecasting, budget analysis, and data analysis. A seasoned user in R, SQL, and Python. My research interests include regional analysis and improving rural outcomes. Most of my projects are centered around creating data/information systems and tools to support my research.

Education

2021 – Present	M.S., Agricultural and Resource Economics, Colorado State University Anticipated graduation in Summer 2023, GPA: 3.8. Working Thesis Title: Exploring a new tourism asset in the context of rural economic development and resiliency; the case of Fishers Peak State Park
2017 – 2021	B.A., Economics, <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8
2017 - 2021	B.S., Computer Information Systems, <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8

Professional Experience

01/2023 – present Denver, CO	Economist & Budget Analyst, State of Colorado In the Tax & Economic Development Division in the Governor's Office of State Planning & Budgeting, duties include: Quarterly Forecasting, Data Management and Visualization, Economic and Revenue Inquiries, & Modeling Development.
08/2021 – Present Fort Collins, CO	Graduate Research Assistant, Colorado State Univesity Apart of the Regional Economic Development Institute (REDI) at CSU. Generate regional economic analysis for on-going projects and as-needed when requested by City/County/State Agencies. Leading website re-design project for more interactive and engaging experience. Primary tools and skills include: R, Python, SQL, econometric analysis, optimization, and WordPress.
01/2022 – 01/2023 Denver, CO	Data Science Intern, City and County of Denver Housed within the Department of Finance, major duties include generating economic analysis,

Housed within the Department of Finance, major duties include generating economic analysis, forecasts, and data science reports for internal and external uses. Internal reports include economic outlook and forecast presentations to the City Council and the Mayor. External facing work includes creating economic indicator dashboards. Daily tasks also include data cleaning, visualization generation, natural language processing (NLP), data mining, named entity recognition (NER), and general consulting with other departments within the city. Primary tools and skills include: R, Python, SQL, Power BI, Visual Basic, ArcGIS, and econometric analysis.

Denver, CO

Data Engineer Intern, Transamerica

Working within Life Technology in Technology Services, I worked on data and API engineering projects using AWS(API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, etc.) and Java (Spring Boot REST API) for maintenance and feature creation for the Financial Services Agent's web services portal. Other core dependencies include Git, JIRA, Terraform, Jenkins, Python, and agile development.

03/2021 – 07/2021

Westlake Village, CA

Provided all operational technology support of the Charter School across two campuses including: Computer tech support and maintenance, Student registration: system support and use, Software and hardware support: troubleshooting and installation, GSuite Administration, Website and social media management, Network management (Cisco Meraki), Photo, video & sound editing (Adobe CC).

Publications

12/2021

Fishers Peak State Park: Evaluating a New Natural Amenity in Southern Colorado,

REDI@CSU 2

The recently christened Fishers Peak State Park offers great potential to give a much-needed boost to the economy of Las Animas County, specifically the town of Trinidad.

Skills

R Shiny, tidyverse, furrr	••••	Python Pandas, Pystat, Jupyter	••••
SQL <i>MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL</i>	••••	AWS API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB	••••
Dashboarding Power BI, Tableau	••••	Web Development HTML/CSS/JS	• • • • •

Courses

Public Budgeting and Finance, Colorado State University

Optimization Methods, Colorado State University

Quantitative Methods, Colorado State University

Applied Econometrics, Colorado State University

Applied Microeconomic Theory, Colorado State University

Applied Welfare and Policy Analysis, Colorado State University

Environmental and Natural Resource Economics, *Colorado State University*

Applied Advanced Water Resource Economics, Colorado State University

Database Management Systems, California Lutheran University

Data Analysis with R, California Lutheran University

Software Engineering, California Lutheran University

Systems Analysis, California Lutheran University

Information, Systems, and Organizational Design, California Lutheran University